Finding aid for Commerce and Industry of Michigan Web Archives, 2010-2014
Bentley Historical Library
Commerce and Industry of Michigan Web Archives
2010-2014
Bentley Historical Library
Bentley Historical Library (collector)
2014025 Aa 3 [2014032]
23 archived websites (online; multiple captures)
Web collection of websites created by various organizations and individuals whose focus is commerce and industry in the State of Michigan, archived by the Bentley Historical Library using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service crawler from 2010-2015 and the Archive-It web archiving service beginning in 2015.
Websites gathered from 2010-2015 using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service web crawler and using the Archive-It web archiving service beginning in 2015.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Michigan's commerce and industry is among Bentley Historical Library's most important topical collection priorities. The topic's priority is based on the Bentley Library's mission as established by the University of Michigan Board of Regents to document "the state, its institutions, and its social, economic, and intellectual development," the historical collecting patterns of the library, and overall collection development priorities in all formats. The process of setting collecting priorities is described by Christine Weideman's "A New Map for Field Work: Impact of Collections Analysis on the Bentley Historical Library" (American Archivist, Winter 1991, Vol. 54 Issue 1, pp. 54-60.) and Judith E. Endelman's "Looking Backward to Plan for the Future: Collection Analysis for Manuscript Repositories." (American Archivist, Summer 1987, Vol. 50 Issue 3, pp. 340-355.)
In selecting web content for permanent preservation, the Bentley Historical Library seeks:
Websites of organizations or individuals whose archives the Library is committed to preserve.
Website that fill gaps in existing collections.
Websites with unique content that documents the work and/or thought process of a person or organization.
Websites that periodically incorporate new content or feature regular updates.
Websites with content that is not likely to be duplicated in an individual or organization's paper records.
As of 2013, the Bentley Library will concentrate efforts on documenting the transformation of Michigan's economy with a focus on the auto industry, emerging industries and the revitalization of Detroit. In addition to these priorities the MHC remains open to the consideration of material with great research potential in any area of Michigan's industrially diverse history.
To learn more about the Bentley Historical Library's Web Archives visit https://archive-it.org/organizations/934.
The Web Archive of Michigan's Commerce and Industry collection contains archived websites created by various businesses and industry driven organizations of the State of Michigan. The websites have been archived by the Bentley Historical Library, using the California Digital Library Web Archiving Service crawler from 2010-2015 and the Archive-It web archiving service beginning in 2015. Access to all websites archived by the Bentley Historical Library is available at: https://archive-it.org/organizations/934.
Web Archives include websites of corporations, small businesses, and nonprofit organizations who call the state of Michigan home. The collection is especially strong in documenting economic development efforts in Detroit and all of Michigan, historic businesses and industries, and distinguished individuals who belong to these communities.
The year that appears next to the website title in the contents list indicates the date that the website was first archived. Archived versions of the site from later dates may also be available.
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Ann Arbor (Mich.) -- Economic conditions.; Art and popular culture -- Michigan.; Bay Harbor (Mich.); Benton Harbor (Mich.); Big Sky (Mont.); Brighton (Utah); Boyne Falls (Mich.); Carrabassett Valley (Me.: Town); Crystal Mountain (Wash.); Detroit (Mich.); Gatlinburg (Tenn.); Harbor Springs (Mich.); Lincoln (N.H.); Mackinac Island (Mich.); Marshall (Mich.) -- Restaurants.; Michigan -- Economic conditions.; Michigan -- Social life and customs.; Newry (Me.); Snoqualmie Pass (Wash.); Washtenaw County (Mich.); Wayne County (Mich.); West Vancouver (B.C.); African Americans -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Architectural firms -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Arab American business enterprises -- Michigan.; Arab Americans -- Michigan.; Architecture -- United States.; Asian Americans -- Michigan.; Automobile industry and trade.; Automobiles -- Design and construction -- Research.; Bankruptcy -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Boards of trade -- Michigan.; Business information services -- Michigan -- Benton Harbor.; Businesspeople -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor.; Charity organizations -- Michigan.; Cities and towns -- Growth -- Michigan.; Commerce and industry.; Corporations -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Digital divide.; Digital media -- Job vacancies -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Downhill skiing.; Entrepreneurs -- Training of -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor.; Environmental protection -- Michigan.; Filipino Americans -- Michigan.; Golf.; Golf resorts.; Hotels -- Michigan -- Mackinac Island.; Information superhighway.; Land use -- Michigan -- Planning.; Liquidation -- Michigan -- Detroit.; Manufactures -- Michigan.; Manufacturing industries -- Government policy -- Michigan.; Manufacturing industries -- Michigan.; New business enterprises -- Michigan.; Nonprofit organizations -- Michigan -- Ann Arbor.; Nonprofit organizations -- Michigan -- Benton Harbor.; Pacific Islander Americans -- Michigan.; Popular music -- United States.; Recreation.; Restaurants -- Michigan -- Marshall.; Russian Americans -- Michigan -- Directories.; Ski resorts.; Sports -- Michigan.; Women journalists -- Michigan.; Blogs.; Brown, Al, 1947-; Albert Kahn Associates.; American Arab Chamber of Commerce.; Ann Arbor SPARK.; Asian Pacific American Chamber of Commerce.; Automation Alley.; Big Sky Resort.; Boyne USA.; Boyne Highlands.; Boyne Mountain.; Center for Automotive Research (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Chrysler LLC.; Community Foundation for Southeast Michigan.; Cornerstone Alliance (Organization); Cypress Mountain.; Detroit Digital Justice Coalition.; Gatlinburg Sky Lift.; General Motors Corporation.; Grand Hotel.; Inn at Bay Harbor.; Jenner & Block LLP.; Loon Mountain.; Michigan Economic Development Corporation.; Michigan Land Use Institute.; Michigan Manufacturer's Association.; Motown Record Corporation -- History.; New Economy Initiative for Southeast Michigan.; Philippine Chamber of Commerce - Michigan.; Schuler's Restaurant & Pub.; Sugarloaf.; Sunday River Resort.; Summit at Snoqualmie.
- Commerce and Industry of Michigan Web Archives
  - Absolute Michigan, 2010
  - Albert Kahn Associates, 2011
  - American Arab Chamber of Commerce, 2011
  - Ann Arbor SPARK, 2011
  - Asian Pacific American Chamber of Commerce, 2011
  - Automation Alley, 2011
  - Boyne USA Resorts, 2011
  - Center for Automation Research, 2011
  - Chrysler LLC Bankruptcy Collection, 2011
  - Detroit Digital Justice Coalition, 2011
  - General Motors Bankruptcy Collection, 2011
  - Grand Hotel, Mackinac Is, 2011
  - Hype&Sou!-The Motown History, 2011
  - Michelle Krebs @AutoObserver.com, 2011
  - Michigan Economic Development Corporation, 2011
  - Michigan Land Use Institute, 2011
  - Michigan Manufacturers Association, 2011
  - New Economy Initiative for Southeast Michigan, 2011
  - Philippine Chamber of Commerce, 2011
  - Russian Michigan Yellow Pages, 2011
  - Schuler's Restaurant & Pub, 2011
  - Southeast Michigan Startup, 2011